Abdiel Orellana

abdielorellana3@gmail.com | github.com/abdiel49 | linkedin.com/in/abdiel-orellana

Summary.

Full Stack Software Developer, Web and Mobile cross platform using React Native & React. Specialized in end-toend development, user friendly UI/UX design. RESTful API development and deployment using NodeJS and SQL and NoSQL databases as well as Docker container management.

Work Experience

Freelancer, Full Stack Software Developer | Remote

Sep 2021 - Dec 2023

- Gathered client requirements and translated them into development tasks and priorities.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to identify product needs and functionality.
- Developed cross-platform mobile applications using React Native.
- Developer of responsive web applications.
- Designed web and mobile user-friendly user interfaces with Figma.
- Building RESTful API servers using NodeJS/NestJS.
- Modeling and implementation of SQL, NoSQL databases.
- Deployed servers and databases in cloud services

tuGerente, Full Stack Software Developer | Remote

Aug 2022 - Feb 2023

- Led mobile development team, responsible for iOS and Android app development and deployment to app stores.
- Managed the end-to-end development process, ensuring high-quality deliverables and meeting project deadlines.
- Assisted the backend team with architecture design, development standards and collaboration.
- Actively contributed to team discussions and provided valuable insights for process improvements.

Canned Head, Front End Developer | Remote

Nov 2021 - Feb 2021

- Frontend development using React, focus on implementing UI designs and ensuring responsive and pixel-perfect web applications.
- Coordinated with the backend team to integrate frontend components with backend APIs.
- Documented code for better maintainability and future reference.

Education_

Bachelor's degree in Informatics Engineering, University Mayor de San Simon | Cochabamba, Bolivia

2017-23

Skills

Programming JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Java, Ruby, C#, C++

Front End React Native, Expo, React, NextJS, VueJS, Redux, Tailwind, Bootstrap, SASS, HTML, CSS

Back End NestJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, TypeORM, Sequelize, Mongoose ODM

Databases PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Realm, PochDB, Apache CouchDB, Firebase

Testing Jest, Testing Library, Cypress, Selenium, Mocha, JUnit

Software Git, Jira, GCP, Linux, Docker, Docker Compose, Figma, XCode, Android Studio, Arduino IDE

Certificates_

2023	Complete iOS Bootcamp - Swift & Objective-C , Udemy - Ongoing	Online
2023	React , Coodesh	Online
2022	React Native , Coursera Meta	Online
2022	Docker Course , Platzi	Online
2022	React Zero to Hero , Udemy Fernando Herrera	Online

Achievements

2023	2nd place, Capture The Flag, International Congress on Computer Security 2023 (CIDSI)	Santa Cruz – Bolivia
2022	5th place, Capture The Flag , International Congress on Computer Security 2022 (CIDSI)	La Paz – Bolivia

Languages

English Intermediate proficiency **Spanish** Native proficiency